in cycle five two things will happen one
this instruction will write its result
and two I'll try to issue the next
instruction if I can we can do that in
either order let's say that we do the
issuing first this time this is a
subtract in Rob five writing to R for R
1 and R 5 r Rob four and three so I
write the value of 3 here and Rob 4 here
and then what I do is I mark the tragedy
step four is from now on going to be
pointing to Rob five because that's
where I put this instruction I have
issued this instruction in cycle five
and with that I have completed the issue
of this instruction but it is not ready
to execute because it still has one of
its operands is not available and we
need to wait for it
another thing again that happens in
cycle five is that we need to take care
of the writing of the result for the Rob
3 instruction so what happens is this
instruction writes the result of 3 with
the tag of Rob 3 now this 3 is really
written here and the instruction is
marked as done also the value of 3 is
broadcast under the name of Rob tree so
that the reservation stations can try to
capture it so what's going to happen is
there is a match here this one is
waiting for Rob 3 it's going to capture
a value of 3 and no longer waits for Rob
3 so this is what happens in cycle 5 as
far as broadcasting of this result is
concerned note that the rat and
everything is not updated yet that will
happen at commit so now in cycle 5 we
have finished our issuing here we have
broadcast the result we are ready to
move on to cycle 6 neither of these
instructions is ready to actually
dispatch in cycle 5 so nothing will
begin executing in cycle 6 because both
of them still wait for something else
so in cycle 6 what happens is as far as
issuing is concerned we're gonna try to
issue this instruction as far as
execution is concerned these two cannot
still execute because they're still
waiting for something as far as writing
of results is concerned the instruction
3 has finished writing the result and
has been marked is done these two still
have a while to go before they're gonna
write the results because we're in
cycles 6 the next thing here is going to
happen in cycle 13 so in cycle 6 pretty
much the only thing that happens is
these two instructions
continue to execute and we try to issue
an instruction we're gonna issue this
one by grabbing a reservation station
and a Rob entry we're gonna be writing
to r1 we are now named Rob six r4 and r2
are coming from Rob five and Rob one so
neither of those is available yet and
then we're gonna mark that r1 from now
on is pointing to Rob six so with this
we have issued this instruction now we
have written the result of this
instruction so technically this
instruction by itself could commit in
cycle six however remember that an
instruction cannot commit until all
previous instructions have committed so
although this instruction would commit
in six if everything else was committed
already it will actually not commit
until at least cycle forty three or four
or five so pretty much this instruction
sits here as done others can use its
result but it cannot really commit until
we commit instructions one and two so in
cycle six this is all that happens there
is no commit here and now we move to
cycles 7 in which case we have nothing
to issue anymore so issuing will not be
an issue anymore we cannot execute
anything until we see some results being
broadcast so really the next cycle when
something interesting will happen is
cycle 13 in which we will have another
write of a result so let's just kind of
fast-forward through to that